SEO YEON (SUNNY) LEE

(702) 498-7457

slee6390@gmail.com

https://github.com/slee6390

Clinical Research Assistant at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center with emphasis on the values of communication and creative problem-solving. Main research experience in clinical interviews, MRI brain segmentation analysis, and mouse behavioral scoring. Additional interests in computer science, human-computer interaction, psychology, and education.

EDUCATION

- October 2023
 Introduction to User Experience Design
 Georgia Institute of Technology (Online)
- June 2023 August 2023

 CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science

 HarvardX (Online)
 - August 2018 May 2022

 Bachelor of Science in Neuroscience, Honors

 Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science

 University of Southern California (USC)

 Los Angeles, CA
 - Graduated summa cum laude (GPA: 3.94/4.00)
 - Neuroscience Honors Thesis: Differential impact of Chd8 haploinsufficiency on social dominance and macrocephaly in two mouse strains
 - USC Dornsife Dean's List (2019 2022)

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- January 2022 May 2022Provost's Research Fellowship
- August 2018 May 2022

 Thematic Option

 Selected for the Thematic Option Honors

 Program, an interdisciplinary core curriculum
 for 200 out of 3,500 freshmen.
- August 2018 May 2022

 Deans Scholarship
- August 2018 May 2019

 Resident Honors Program (RHP)

 Selected as one of the 20 international students to bypass the senior year and commence studies at the University of Southern California as a freshman.

SKILLS

Clinical research

• Clinical interviews, patient consent forms, study protocols, and IRB submissions

Data collection and analysis

• RedCap, SPSS, Graphpad Prism, AMIRA, BORIS, and Excel

Programming languages

Working knowledge of C, Python, Javascript, HTML/CSS, SQL, and Git

Languages

• English (bilingual), Korean (bilingual), Spanish (conversational)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2022 - Present

Clinical Research Assistant | Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) | Boston, MA

- Project coordinator of a NIH-funded research project, What the Nose Knows: Hedonic Capacity,
 Psychosocial Interventions and Outcomes in Schizophrenia
- Obtain informed consent from approximately 120 study participants
- Conduct clinical interviews of individuals diagnosed with schizophrenia to gather comprehensive data related to olfaction, negative symptoms, and hedonic capacity
- Organize and manage clinical data to maintain a record of participants of the study, detailing their information and gathered data using RedCap, Excel, and Microsoft Teams
- Draft and submit documents and reports as required by the Institutional Review Board and National Institute of Mental Health
- Train and advise new staff in procedures and protocols

June 2020 - Present

Tutor in SAT, Reading, Grammar, and Mathematics | Online

- Provide one-on-one instructions through online Zoom meetings, developing tailored teaching materials and resources for diverse Korean students, ranging from those in elementary school to adults preparing for the Korean Civil Service Exam
- Enhance test performance up to 300 points for the SAT
- Conduct assessments, monitors academic advancements, and maintains effective communication with both students and parents to provide timely progress updates

January 2019 – May 2022

Research Assistant Levitt Laboratory, Children's Hospital Los Angeles | Los Angeles, CA

- Conducted research under the guidance of Dr. Pat Levitt, focusing on the genetic factors influencing individual variations in social behavior and learning abilities
- Led a project involving the analysis of MRI images of mouse brains to quantify both overall brain volume and specific regions of interest and used the project's findings to compile an Honors Thesis paper highlighting significant genotype-dependent effects influenced by sex and strain, demonstrating how structural brain differences contribute to behavioral variations among strains
- Assessed Direct Social Interaction videos, organized data, conducted graphical and statistical analyses, managed of the mouse colony, and ran behavioral experiments with mice

May 2021 – May 2022

Mentor-Mentee Relations Chair | WAZO, USC Chapter | Los Angeles, CA

- Initiated and introduced the use of REDCap to establish and manage the mentor-mentee database for this newly founded organization at USC
- Successfully paired around 40 mentors and mentees based on shared identities, personalities, and interests
- Played a key role in the organization's expansion through active recruitment, innovative idea generation, and the establishment of new protocols to enhance overall efficiency
- Provided presentations and organized office hours to assist mentors and mentees in troubleshooting issues as needed

PRESENTATIONS

- Schutt, R., **Lee, S.**, Xie, H., Mueser, K., Killam, M., Delman, J., Eack, S., Mesholam-Gately, R., Pratt, S., Sandoval, L., Santos, M., Golden, L., & Keshavan, M. (2023, March 1). *Cognitive Enhancement Therapy vs Social Skills Training in schizophrenia: a cluster randomized comparative effectiveness evaluation.* [Poster Session]. Harvard Psychiatry Day and Mysell Lecture, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.
- Lee, S., Tabbaa M., Knoll A., & Levitt P. (2022, January 20 22). Differential impact of Chd8 haploinsufficiency on social dominance and macrocephaly in two mouse strains. [Poster Session]. Ygnite KSEA (Korean-American Scientists and Engineers Association), Atlanta, GA, United States.
- Tabbaa M., Knoll A., **Lee, S.**, & Levitt P. (2021, December 13 15). *Integrating genetically diverse mouse reference panels with mutations in an autism risk gene to discover mechanisms regulating social behavioral heterogeneity.* [Conference Session]. Society for Social Neuroscience conference, online.